A Guide to the Film collection FA466
Rockefeller Archive Center
Film collection
undated
Rockefeller Archive Center
FA466
1500 film reels Approximately 1500 films.
Approximately 1500 films.
Conditions Governing Access
When requesting to view films -- please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1902).
If the item does not have a designated AV number, please refer to the Title and the Film Number (which consists of a combination of Roman numerals and alphanumerics - example: III 14.1-6).
Arrangement
The films are arranged into 23 series based primarily on original provenance. When provenance is unknown, material is designated according to the subject matter and/or the primary individual/institution associated with the given subject or activity.
Series 1: AIA/IBEC. Series 2: Asia Society. Series 3: John C. Bugher. Series 4: Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA). Series 5: Harold P. Fabian. Series 6: Ford Foundation. Series 7: Frederick W. Knipe. Series 8: Rockefeller family, General. Series 9: John D. Rockefeller. Series 10: John D. Rockefeller Jr. Series 11: Abby Rockefeller Mauze ("Babs") Series 12: John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Series 13: Nelson A. Rockefeller, Personal. Series 14: Nelson A. Rockefeller, Political Career. Series 15: Laurance S. Rockefeller. Series 16: Winthrop Rockefeller. Series 17: David Rockefeller. Series 18: Rockefeller Foundation. Series 19: Rockefeller University. Series 20: Paul Ehrlich. Series 21: Paul A. Weiss Laboratory. Series 22: William H. Whyte. Series 23: General or Miscellaneous films.
Conditions Governing Access note
All inquires to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those that are not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
Separated Materials note
The majority of Films have been physically separated from an archival collection.
In most cases, the specific details of the provenance are simply unknown.
Scope and Contents note
The Film collection is an artificial collection created by the RAC in order to efficiently and effectively manage and present the moving images held among our archival holdings.
This material includes films and moving images in virtually every format available since the early 20th century including but not necessarily limited to: 16mm, 35mm, beta, Super 8, VHS and DVD.
- AIA/IBEC, 1
  Scope and Contents
  The RAC has a collection of films in English and Spanish made for the use of IBEC, including films on tropical diets, agricultural practices and improvements, housing in Puerto Rico, and food production.
  Biographical / Historical
  The American International Association for Economic and Social Development was established by Nelson Rockefeller in 1946 as an outgrowth of his work as Coordinator for Inter-American Affairs. With a similar mission, the International Basic Economy Corporation was established in 1947 to enhance the economic and social growth of developing countries, particularly in Latin America.
  Arrangement
  Alphabetical.
  - La Batilla Contra La Huja Blanca, Silent, Black & white, 5 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1263, Reel IV 3B2 Fb 2)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    All inquires to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
    Scope and Contents note
    produced by AIA/El Observador Creole/Bolivar Films, Curacas, Venezuela
  - Good Diets in the Tropics, Sound (in English or in Spanish), Black & white, 15 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel IV 3B2Fb 7, Reel AV 870)
    Produced by AIA/Knickerbocker Productions for Consejo Informativo de Educacion Alimenticia (Advisory Board on Food and Education); producer Schuyler Bradt, director Victor Solow
  - Crucito: Una Realizacion de Extension Agricola, Sound, Color, 12 minutes, only available on original 16mm film. (Reel IV 3B2 Fb 1, Reel AV 1262)
    Produced by IBEC/Ministry of Culture/ABN Film Production, Caracas, Venezuela
  - El Cultivo del Cafe in Venezuela (The Cultivation of Coffee in Venezuela), 1958; Sound, color, 13 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel IV 3B2 Fd 4, Reel AV 1260)
    Produced by MAC Film, with CBR Coordination/ABN Film
  - The IBEC System of Low-Cost Housing Construction, Sound, Black & white, 15 minutes, Only available on original 35mm film. (Reel IV 3B2 Fg 1, Reel AV 1093)
    Overview of techniques and machinery used to construct inexpensive concrete homes, based on plan by Nelson A. Rockefeller and architect Wallace K. Harrison; produced by RKO/Pathe
  - La Produccion de Leche (Milk Production), Sound, Color, 15 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1526, Reel IV 382 Fd 1)
    Produced by Aquila Films/MAC/CBR
  - Semeando Para u Futuro (Seeding the Future), Sound, Black & white, 20 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel IV 3B2 Fd 5, Reel AV 1264)
    Dramatic portrayal of ACAR/IBE projects to improve agricultural, economic, and social conditions in Brazil, told through the story of a poor tobacco farmer and his family. The organizations introduce "modern methods" for irrigation and planting, harvest and milling, washing, cooking, and others. Produced by AIA/Cine Films, with Herbert Riche.
  - Lomas Verdes, 1956 August 5; Silent, Black & white, 2 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel IV 3B21 Fa 2, Fa 3, Reel AV 1092, Reel AV 1091)
    Puerto Rican television piece on Lomas Verdes, the IBEC housing corporation of Puerto Rico. Filmed and broadcast by Telemando TV-WKAQ.
  - This is America: Rockefeller Center, Sound, Black & white, 30 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel IV 3B2 Fd 2, Fd3, Reel AV 1088, Reel AV 1259)
    An RKO newsreel relating to IBEC projects
  - Vineta Verficando Posibilidados en Oriente (Survey for the Future in Eastern Venezuela), Sound (in English), Black & white, 10 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1526, Volume IV 3B2 Fb 4)
    A summary of research being conducted in hopes of improving agricultural development, as well as aiding social and economic causes. Produced by El Observador Creole/Bolivar Films
  - Visita Ministro Iraq y Sr. Rockefeller, 1957 September 21; Silent, Black & white, 2 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1090, Reel IV 3B21 Fa 1)
    Winthrop Rockefeller visits IBEC housing projects with Iraqi ministers in Puerto Rico
  - Weed and Brush Control, Silent, color, 9 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1522, Volume IV 3B21 Ff 1)
    Tradewind Air Spray, Amarillo, Texas
  - Youth Club Achievement Day, Silent, Black & white, 5 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1817, Volume IV 3B2 Fc 1)
    Display of traditional cooking, dancing, farming, and fashion styles by youth clubs in Aragua, Venezuela. Presented to administrators, foreign visitors, and military personnel.
- Asia Society, 2
  - Asia Society: Bali, Silent, Black & white, 8 minutes. (Reel IV 3B6 Fb 4)
    Footage of ceremonial dances with and without traditional costumes
  - Asia Society, WNET (Reel IV 3B6 F 45)
  - Asia Society Fair (Reel IV 3B6 F 47)
  - Bali (Reel IV 3B6 Fb 8)
  - Bodoyo Dancers, Silent, Black & white, 12 minutes. (Reel IV 3B6 Fb 6, Reel IV 3B6 Fb 5)
    Buddhist temple with musicians, group of female court dancers
  - Bull Races, c. 1920s; Silent, Black & white, 6 minutes. (Reel IV 3B6 Fb 11)
    Festival with dancing and important citizens
  - Celebese, c. 1920s; Silent, Black and white, 12 minutes. (Reel IV 3B6 Fb 2)
    Views of and from boat; passengers and crowds along water's edge; waterfall; ceremonial dances; village market; parade.
  - Crafts, Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes. (Reel IV 3B6 Fb 12)
    Footage of brass production and wood-carving
  - Dutch Ship, c. 1920s; Silent, Black and white, 8 minutes. (Reel IV 3B6 Fb 10)
    Harbor scenes, small sailing craft, barges, passengers debarking, rickshaws, city scenes.
  - Farmers, c. 1920s; Silent, Black and white, 11 minutes. (Reel IV 3B6 Fb 1)
    View of rice terraces, plowing with oxen, cutting sugar cane
  - Groundbreaking Ceremony (Reel IV 3B6 F 44)
  - An Interview with Indira Gandhi, 1975; Silent, Color, 28 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1781, Reel IV 3B6 F46)
    From a Canadian news source, a profile of Indian Prime Minister Indira Gandhi. Shown at work and at home, the episode discusses Gandhi's career and authority amidst a state of emergency and accusations of tyranny. Produced and directed by Paul Saltzman: a Sunrise Films LTD Production
  - Java (Reel 1): Race, Nias, Sultan's Court, Silent, Black & white, length unknown. (Reel IV 3B6 Fg 1)
  - Java (Reel 2): Court Jogjakarta, Silent, Black & white, length unknown. (Reel IV 3B6 Ff 5)
  - Java (Reel 3): Clowns, Love Dance, Solo Sultan Funeral, Silent, Black & white, length unknown. (Reel IV 3B6 Ff 2)
  - Kraton Surakarta dan Sekitarnya, Silent, Black & white, 33 minutes. (Reel IV 3B6 Fe 3)
    footage of bull races, ceremonial dances with men and women, a royal funeral with procession and puppet show, and a temple
  - Markets, Silent, Black & white, 4 minutes. (Reel IV 3B6 Fb 9)
    Complete scenes from Indonesia film
  - Mission to Yemen (Reel IV 3B6 F 43)
  - Sugar Plantation (Reel IV 3B6 Fe 4)
- John C. Bugher, 3; The entire Bugher Collection was digitized in 2011 and is available for viewing on DVD.
  Dr. Bugher was a staff member of the Rockefeller Foundation and worked with the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission.
  The RAC has a number of films from the 1920s and 1930s that show Bugher's work on yellow fever in Africa, the Balkans, Greece, and South America. Scenes of villages and traditional practices, malaria treatments, efforts to combat mosquitoes, and some later footage relating to the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission (ca. 1950-1960).
  - Africa, Silent, Color, 10 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 1, Dvd AV 836, Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 15, Reel AV 836)
    Footage from Nigeria and Lagos; rural villages; inspecting school children; the Yellow Fever Research Institute; Asibi
  - Albania - Sardinia - Terracina, 1931; Silent, Black & white, 8 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 17, Box 1, Dvd AV 838, Reel AV 838)
    Dr. Bishop and Dr. Smillie at work; irrigation plant at Porta Torros; spraying equipment on boat. Produced by Frederick Knipe
  - Columbia, Silent, Black & white, 4 minutes. Available on DVD. (Volume IV 2A 2.7 Fb 5, Box 1, Dvd AV 829, Reel AV 829)
    Footage of rivers, mountains villages, paddle wheel boat pulling logs
  - Columbia, 1928; Silent, Black & white, 12 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 12, Box 1, Dvd AV 832, Reel AV 832)
    Footage of religious processions, mountains, waterfalls, native fishermen; aerial views of jungle. Produced by H.H. Howard
  - Columbia, Silent, Color, 22 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 835, Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 14, Box 1, Dvd AV 835)
    Footage of vaccination program, lab work, rural villages, deforestation
  - Greece, 1930; Silent, Black & white, 10 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 833, Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 13, Box 1, Dvd AV 833)
    Footage of unsystematic irrigation set-up, a main source of malaria. Villagers washing in contaminated dam; superpictus found in all water sources. Produced by Lewis Hackett.
  - Jungle Yellow Fever, Sound, Color, 21 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 1, Dvd AV 841, Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fd 1, Reel AV 841)
    Footage showing sanitary conditions in Buenaventura, Bogota, Columbia, yellow fever research and vaccination efforts. Produced by the Columbian, government with I.H.D. Photography, J.C. Bugher, and Hartley Productions.
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    Two copies of access DVD.
  - Malaria in Bulgaria, Silent, Black & white, 11 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 839, Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 18, Box 1, Dvd AV 839)
    Footage of scientists inspecting canals, with technical data
  - O Brasil Naera Atomica, Sound, Black & white, 9 minutes. Available on DVD. (Volume IV 2A 2.7 Fb 6, Reel AV 830, Box 1, Dvd AV 830)
    Footage of International Atomic Energy Agency installation (atomic energy exhibit) in Brazil; medical and industrial uses, UN presentation. In Portuguese. Produced by Atualidades Brasileiras Films, producer Herbert Richers.
  - South America, Silent, Black & white, 4 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 828, Box 1, Dvd AV 828, Volume IV 2A 2.7 Fb 4)
    South American jewelry and craft; footage of procession and mule packs
  - Villavincencio, Silent, Black & white, 9 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 837, Box 1, Dvd AV 837, Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 16)
  - West Africa #1, 1931; Silent, Black & white, 9 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 823, Box 1, Dvd AV 823, Volume IV 2A 2.7 Fb 1)
    Footage of natives in canoes, village culture, and the Yellow Fever Research Institute (reel 1 of 3). Produced by F. F. Russell.
  - West Africa #2, 1926; Silent, Black & white, 11 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 1, Dvd AV 824A, Reel AV 824A, Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 9)
    Footage of the Yellow Fever Commission work in Lagos: payday for natives, mosquito research, life along the Ogun River (reel 2 of 3). Produced by W.A Sawyer.
  - West Africa #2, 1931; Silent, Black & white, 10 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 1, Dvd AV 825, Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 2, Reel AV 825)
    Footage of natives in canoes, village culture, and the Yellow Fever Research Institute (reel 2 of 2). Produced by F. F. Russell
  - West Africa #3, 1926; Silent, Black & white, 9 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 1, Dvd AV 824B, Reel AV 824B, Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 10)
    Footage of the Yellow Fever Commission work: scenes in Oshogbo, Clesha, Oyo; women spinning thread, bagging cotton; Baptist Hospital African Mission (reel 3 of 3). Produced by W.A. Sawyer
  - West African Dancers, Silent, Black & white, 9 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 1, Dvd AV 831, Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 7, Reel AV 831)
    Footage of a dance troupe practicing acrobatic routines.
  - West Africa Yellow Fever, 1926; Silent, Black & white, 9 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 1, Dvd AV 826, Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 8, Reel AV 826)
    Footage of the Yellow Fever Commission work in Nigeria and Lagos: fishing, natives at work, parades, dancing, religious rites (reel 1 of 3). Produced by W.A. Sawyer.
  - Yaba, Silent, Black & white, 9 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 1, Dvd AV 827, Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 3, Reel AV 827)
    Footage of village houses, rural roads, women carrying vegetation
  - Yellow Fever Research Institute (Nigeria), Silent, Black & white, 9 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel IV 2A 2.7 Fb 11, Box 1, Dvd AV 840, Reel AV 840)
    Footage of main lab and equipment, lab work, taking blood samples, mosquito traps; shots of an eclipse
- Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA), 4; All of the CIAA films are available on DVD, except where noted.
  Under Nelson Rockefeller, the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs was created to support various health and social wellness initiatives, as well as to maintain cultural and commercial relations between North and South America. From 1940 to 1946, the CIAA used films and posters to advertise their projects in Argentina, Bolivia, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Haiti, Mexico, Peru, Uruguay, and Venezuela.
  In 1942, the CIAA contracted Walt Disney Studios to produce 18 films, all of which are available at the RAC. An additional set of films produced by the Julien Bryan Studio created for a primary and secondary level school audience were not commissioned individually by the CIAA, but are included here because of their related content. Many of these films are in Spanish, and some are animated features, or a combination of animation and live-action.
  There is a substantial amount of documentation about these films in the Nelson Rockefeller papers. These reels, including the material produced by Walt Disney Productions, are thought to be Nelson Rockefeller’s personal copies.
  - The Amazon Awakens, 1944; Sound, Color, 90 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 40 F 55, Box 2, Dvd AV 1269, Reel AV 1269)
    History and future of the Amazon Basin region.
  - Argentine Primer, Sound, Black & white, 23 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1270, Reel III 40 F 31, Box 2, Dvd AV 1270)
    Overview of urban and rural life, culture, industries, exports; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
  - Belo Horizonte, Sound, Black & white, 17 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 40 F 43, Reel AV 1271, Box 2, Dvd AV 1271)
    Planned city expansion, Brazil: growth, industry, housing and institutions. Produced by the CIAA/ Office of Strategic Services.
  - Bolivia, Sound, Black & white, 20 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1272, Reel III 40 F 39, Box 2, Dvd AV 1272)
    Rubber industry, geography, mining, agriculture; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
  - Brazil, Sound/Silent, Color, 18 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 40 F 61, Reel AV 1273, Box 2, Dvd AV 1273)
    Footage of Rio, Sao Paulo, coffee production, and a poisonous snake ranch.
  - The Bridge, Sound, Black & white, 30 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 40 F 56, Box 2, Dvd AV 1274, Reel AV 1274)
    Overview of South American industry, economy, agriculture, and the underutilization of resources, with a look towards future development with the aid of air transportation. Presented by Documentary Films Production and the Foreign Policy Association along with the CIAA.
  - Columbia: Crossroads of the Americas, Sound, Black & white, 26 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1275, Reel AV 1275, Reel III 40 F 57)
    Overview of Colombian geography, history, agriculture, industry, culture, and politics; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
  - El Cuerpo Humano (The Human Body), 1944; Sound, Color, 9 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1276, Box 2, Dvd AV 1276, Reel III 40 F 16)
    Animated feature about the components of the human body, and what is required to keep healthy; presented by Walt Disney Studios, as part of the "Health for the Americas" series
  - El Cuidado del Nino (Infant Care), 1944; Sound, Color, 9 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1277, Box 2, Dvd AV 1277, Reel III 40 F 13)
    Animated feature about the components of the human body and what is required to keep; presented by Walt Disney Studios as part of the "Health for Americas" series.
  - Defensa Contra La Invasion (Defense Against Invasion), 1944; Sound, Color, 12 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1278, Reel AV 1278, Reel III 40 F 12)
    Animated feature about infection and the effectiveness of vaccines; presented by Walt Disney Studios.
  - Down Where North Begins, Sound, Color, 20 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1279, Reel AV 1279, Reel III 40 F 44)
    Tour of Ecuador: cities, villages, mountains, traditional activities like spinning wool, weaving, and hunting. Produced by Herbert Knapp Productions and narrated by Ben Graver (not commissioned by the CIAA).
  - La Enfermedad se Propoga (How Disease Spreads), 1944; Sound, Color, 10 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1280, Reel AV 1280, Reel III 40 F 14)
    Animated feature on polluted water, insects, and poor hygiene and sanitation; presented by Walt Disney Studios as part of the "Health for the Americas"
  - Es Facil Comer Bien (It is Easy to Eat Well), 1945; Sound, Color, 8 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1281, Reel AV 1281, Reel III 40 F 20)
    Animated feature on the needs and benefits of a well-balanced diet, and how to create healthy meals at home; produced by Walt Disney Studios, as part of the "Health for the Americas" series
  - Fundo In Chile, Sound, Black & white, 20 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 40 F 33, Box 2, Dvd AV 1282, Reel AV 1282)
    Film about life and agriculture on a large family estate; presented by Julien Bryan Productions
  - Good Neighbor Family, Sound, Black & white, 16 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 40 F 27, Box 2, Dvd AV 1283, Reel AV 1283)
    Urban and rural life throughout Latin America; presented by Julien Bryan Productions
  - Guadalajara, Sound, Color, 17 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 40 F 46, Reel AV 1284, Box 2, Dvd AV 1284)
    Tour of the city: architecture, art, pottery, seascapes; produced by the Mexican Tourism Department and narrated by Walter Abel.
  - The High Plain, Sound, Black & white, 19 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 40 F 40, Reel AV 1285, Box 2, Dvd AV 1285)
    Life of the Indians on a hacienda in Bolivia; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
  - La Historia de Jose (The Story of Jose), 1944; Sound, Color, 11 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1286, Reel III 40 F 8, Box 2, Dvd AV 1286)
    Animated feature from Walt Disney Studios, part of the "Reading for the Americas" series (# 3).
  - La Historia de Ramon (The Story of Ramon), 1944; Sound, Color, 11 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1287, Reel III 40 F 10, Box 2, Dvd AV 1287)
  - Housing in Chile, Sound, Black & white, 18 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1288, Reel III 40 F 30, Box 2, Dvd AV 1288)
    Story of a family working within the government?s improved housing plan; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
  - El Imperio Inca (The Incan Empire), Sound, Color, 21 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1509, Reel III 40 F 46)
    General note
    Spanish.
    Study of Incan ruins and architecture in present-day Cuzco, Peru
  - Inauguration of President Vargas (Brazil), 1951; Silent and sound, Black & white, 13 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 40 F 42, Reel AV 1290, Box 2, Dvd AV 1290)
    Newsreel footage of international leaders, including NAR, in ceremonial garb, with greeting in Portuguese from President Vargas
  - Insectos Que Transmitten Enfermedes (Insects that Transmit Diseases), 1945; Sound, Color, 8 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1291, Reel AV 1291, Reel III 40 F 18)
    Animated feature about lice, mosquitoes, flies, and other harmful pests and their removal; presented by Walt Disney Studios
  - Inspection of Women's Service Units, 1951 March 3; Silent, Black & white, 9 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1292, Reel AV 1292, Reel III 40 F 5)
    Film of a visit of the Norfolk Naval Air Station, Langley Air Force Base, and WAC Base. Produced by the U.S. Department of Defense
  - Introduction to Haiti, Sound, Color, 10 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1289, Box 2, Dvd AV 1289, Reel III 40 F 4)
    Footage of Port Au Prince: the market, language, traditions, and politics of the people. Presented by Mary Darling Productions; narrated by Milton J. Cross
  - Jose Como Bien (Jose Eats Well), 1944; Sound, Color, 11 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1293, Box 2, Dvd AV 1293, Reel III 40 F 9)
    Animated feature from Walt Disney Studios, part of the "Reading for the Americas" series (# 2).
  - Lima, Sound, Black & white, 15 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1295, Reel AV 1295, Reel III 40 F 49)
    Life, health, art, and education in the urban center; presented by Julien Bryan Productions
  - Lima Family, Sound, Black & white, 18 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1296, Reel AV 1296, Reel III 40 F 34)
    Life of an upper/middle class family in Peru; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
  - La Limpieza Trae Buena Salud (Cleanliness Brings Good Health), 1944; Sound, Color, 8 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1297, Reel AV 1297, Reel III 40 F 15)
    Animated feature comparing sanitary and unsanitary living conditions; produced by Walt Disney Studios as part of the "Health in the Americas" series
  - Mexico Builds a Democracy, Sound, Color, 19 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1298, Box 2, Dvd AV 1298, Reel III 40 F 50)